all right the JFS formerly the Jews free
school has an admissions policy that
gives preference to children who are
recognized as Jewish according to the
Orthodox Jewish religion this means that
the child's mother must either be
descended from a Jewish mother herself
or have converted to Judaism in
accordance with the requirements of
Jewish orthodoxy this appeal is about a
boy whose mother converted to Judaism in
a way that did not satisfy the Orthodox
requirements he was refused entry to the
school his father challenged the
admissions policy on the ground that in
discriminating against those who had not
recognised as Jewish it breached the
race relations act that act forbids
discrimination on the ground of ethnic
origin the majority of the court has
concluded that the JFS admission policy
does discriminate on the ground of
ethnic origin and is in consequence
unlawful the minority disagrees
considering that the admission
requirement is exclusively a religious
requirement that does not depend on
ethnic origin the majority have made it
plain in their judgments that the fact
that the JFS admission policy has fallen
foul of the race relations act certainly
does not mean that those responsible for
the admission policy have behaved in a
way that is racist as that word is
generally understood in the result the
substantive appeal is dismissed the
appeal on costs of the United synagogue
is allowed to the
sit out in the judgment of Lord hope
[Applause]